LinkedIn: nitish-mani-379839223

Github: <u>nitish-mani</u> Leetcode: <u>nitishmani63</u>

Professional Summ	ary	/
-------------------	-----	---

Full-stack Developer experienced working with front-end and back-end frameworks including, Java, JavaScript, React, Node JS, Express JS, Mongodb, Mongoose. Also, I have full command of HTML, CSS, React, Express JS, Mongodb, Mongoose. I possess high communication skills, both written and oral in addition and by all these abilities I can take your company to the highest level in the market with my coworkers at the team level.

____ Education

Year	Degree/Examination	Institution/Board	CGPA/Percentage
2022	Master of Arts (Sociology)	DEEN DAYAL UPADHYAYA GORAKHPUR UNIVERSITY GORAKHPUR	52.0%
2020	Bachelor of Arts (Economics)	DEEN DAYAL UPADHYAYA GORAKHPUR UNIVERSITY GORAKHPUR	56.0%
2014	Intermediate (Class XII)	AYT SR SEC SCH VILL GHATAILA CHETIE DEORIA UP	58.0%
2012	Matriculation (Class X)	SARASWATI SR SEC VIDYA MANDIR DEORIA KHAS DEORIA UP	82.0%

___ Experience

A Y T College Deoria | MERN Stack Tutor

October 2023 - March 2024

MERN Stack Instructor

Justdial | CIC

July 2023 - September 2023

Sales Executive

Projects

Aapka kaam | Full Stack Developer (link)

December 2023 - April 2024

Features

- Users can access variety of services
- Users must signup and login to avail services
- User can book services

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, REACT, EXPRESS JS, REST API, MONGOOSE, and AWS for server hosting

Description: Users can get their work done in real time basis

Lawzon India (Freelancing) | Lawzon India (link)

July 2023 - August 2023

Features

- \bullet Users can submit their requirements related to trademarks, copyrights, etc
- Users can contact admin using what's app
- Admin can login and see user's data which is submitted by users
- Admin can mark data as read or unread in his dashboard

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, REACT, EXPRESS, REST API, MONGODB, MONGOOSE, and AWS for server hosting

Description: Users can get their work done by admin in real time basis

Certifications

NEWTON SCHOOL | Newton School Coding Bootcamp

July 2022

- Full Stack Web Development and Data Structures With Problem Solving Skills.
- Tech Stack Learnt: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB, Mongoose and Java.
- Participated in coding competitions held by Newton School.
- Worked on various projects.

_ Skills

Computer languages HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java

Software Packages NodeJS, Express JS, Mongo DB, React

Additional Courses Taken Data Structure

Soft Skills Public speaking, Creativity, Teamwork, Critical Thinking, Responsibility, Communication Skills